Guide to the Daniel Mazia Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Daniel Mazia papers
1969-1996
SC0704
Mazia, Daniel, 1912-
Mazia, Daniel
25 Linear feet
Papers include correspondence, research notes, organizational files (including the International Cell Research Organization), course files, publications and reprints, photographs, and videotapes.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Access: collection is unprocessed; please consult the University Archivist for access.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Daniel Mazia, cell biologist, was professor emeritus at Stanford University's Hopkins Marine Station at the time of his death in 1996. He earned his Ph.D. at the University of Pennsylvania in 1937. He taught at the University of Missouri (1938-50) and UC Berkeley (1951-79) before joining Stanford's faculty. He was a member of the National Academy of Sciences and the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.
Description of the Collection
Papers include correspondence, research notes, organizational files (including the International Cell Research Organization), course files, publications and reprints, photographs, and videotapes.
Access Terms
Hopkins Marine Station--Faculty.; International Cell Research Organization.; Mazia, Daniel; Molecular biology.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Correspondence 1969-96 (outgoing chron + letters of reference) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence incoming, A-KAL (Box 2)
  - Correspondence incoming, KAO-Z (Box 3)
  - Organization files: ICRO 1980-94 (International Cell Research Organization) (Box 4)
  - Organization files: ICRO 1995-96 and others (Box 5)
  - Research files (notes), 1974-77 (Box 6)
  - Research files (notes), 1978-81 (Box 7)
  - Research files (notes), 1981-82 (Box 8)
  - Research files (notes), 1983-85 (Box 9)
  - Research files (notes), 1986-96 (Box 10)
  - Research files (photographs) (Box 11)
  - Research files (photographs and figures) (Box 12)
  - National Academy of Science files, Proceedings of the NAS, and other grant files (Box 13)
  - National Science Foundation files (Box 14)
  - Class files, student papers, etc. (Box 15)
  - Personal papers, biographical information, trip files, lectures (Box 16)
  - Writings, subject files, miscellaneous files (Box 17)
  - Unprocessed (mostly publications) (Box 18)
  - Unprocessed (photos, negs, illustrations, reprints) (Box 19)
  - Unprocessed (reprints and publications) (Box 20)
  - Unprocessed (publications) (Box 21)
  - Unprocessed (mostly publications and reprints) (Box 22)
  - Unprocessed (video tapes) (Box 23)
  - Unprocessed (video tapes and computer disks) (Box 24)
  - Unprocessed (papers) (Box 25)
  - Unprocessed (mostly negatives and prints) (Box 26)
  - Unprocessed (videos and films) (Box 27)
  - Unprocessed (slides, mostly larger format) (Box 28)
  - Slides (35mm format), arranged (Box 29)
  - Unprocessed (diplomas, one os photo montage) (Box 30)